<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/tag/about/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2020-04-27T22:33:13+09:00</updated>
  <id>http://localhost:4000/tag/about/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Hailey’s Programming Blog | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>...is under construction! Come back later!</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Welcome to my blog!</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/welcome" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to my blog!" />
      <published>2020-04-23T19:00:00+09:00</published>
      <updated>2020-04-23T19:00:00+09:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/welcome</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/welcome">&lt;p&gt;Hi, I’m Hailey!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m a &lt;strong&gt;software engineer&lt;/strong&gt; studying Mathematics and Computing science at Simon Fraser University, Vancouver, BC. I like finding patterns and solving challenging problems. I spend my free time writing codes, debugging them until they work, and hanging out with my nerdy friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is more about me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Math &amp; Computer Science&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m a third year undergraduate student majoring in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sfu.ca/students/calendar/2020/summer/programs/mathematics-and-computing-science/joint-major/bachelor-of-science.html&quot;&gt;Mathematics and Computing Science (a.k.a. MACM)&lt;/a&gt;. MACM is a program for students who came to decide their major between (1) Mathematics and (2) Computing Science, and thought:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;“Why give up one? Let’s learn both!”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes! I am a programmer with strong mathematical background, or in other direction, a mathematician with strong programming skills. I enjoy applying data structures and algorithms while solving programming problems. You can see my codes &lt;a&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My university goal is to be able to understand any math / computer related papers and articles I want to read myself. (Write some more here)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;My Projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a&gt;Special Fortification Unit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(TODO: Put some image and write more)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special Fortification Unit (S.F.U.) is a web-based, real-time, multiplayer survival
    game (with a twist!) set at SFU Burnaby. Four students come to SFU for classes on a snowy
    day. Due to heavy snowfall, their classes get cancelled, leaving the students stranded on
    campus. Then, some mysterious enemies attack! Dear SFU students, we know you are
    already burned out from assignments and exams, but please stay safe from the evil
    enemies! The game features playable maps based on the SFU Burnaby campus and four
    playable characters cooperating with each other. Mysterious enemies with different attack
    patterns, as well as intuitive leveling, health, and money systems provide an excellent
    experience for players.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a&gt;ColorQuirrel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ColorQuirrel is a MATLAB image processing program that plays around color spaces. It converts the image to several different ways to represent the data, extracts the representative color from the image by clustering the data, and uses down-sampling method to speed up the procedure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a&gt;Sapiens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sapiens is a human civilization simulator written in Javascript. (TODO: Write more)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Favorite Tools&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(TODO: Write this)&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This blog is not done. Come back later!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Hailey Ahn</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="about" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Hi, I’m Hailey! I’m a software engineer studying Mathematics and Computing science at Simon Fraser University, Vancouver, BC. I like finding patterns and solving challenging problems. I spend my free time writing codes, debugging them until they work, and hanging out with my nerdy friends. Below is more about me!</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
